

Hamza Shafique – Performance Marketing

Google Ads | Facebook Ads | Amazon Ads

Johar Town, Lahore, Pakistan haamza@live.co.uk -- +92 321 4847656 -- +1 315 407 6426

Relentlessly resourceful marketing professional with 8+ Years of experience managing clients on Digital Spectrum, particularly performance marketing. Specializes in creating and implementing innovative cross channel media strategies coupled with strong business understanding, that are designed to increase customer acquisitions and improve key business metrics.

Skills

Search Engine Marketing

Amazon Private Label Management

Social Media Marketing

Online Brand Building/Lead Generation

Microsoft Excel

Amazon Private Label PPC

Market Research

Professional Experience

E-COMMERCE PLANNERS

January 2022 – Present

Operations Lead - Performance Marketing

- Design and implement social media and PPC strategies to align with business goals of the clients
- For Ecommerce clients, maintain the ROAS while increasing revenue for the clients
- Launch of new brands on Digital and Amazon from Brand Building to store engagement and performance marketing
- Launching of multiple brands on Amazon from scratch including Product Research,
 Product Sourcing, Listing Optimization and then Launch & Rank on Amazon for both US and UK Markets
- Successfully managing over 25 clients on Amazon platform from inventory management to ratings and PPC
- Expertise in running Sponsored Ads, Sponsored Brands, Display Ads, DSP, VIS (Video-in-Search) Ads

SYSTEMS LIMITED

September 2017 – December 2021

Senior Manager - Digital Marketing

- Design and implement social media strategy to align with business goals
- Managing/supervising campaigns for all clients of the company
- Responsible for Planning, Managing and supervising various sort of Analysis to keep the accounts profitable
- Collaborate with other teams, like marketing, sales and customer service to ensure brand consistency

- Provides short- and long-term market forecasts and reports by directing market research collection, analysis, and interpretation of market data
- Looking for ways to add more revenue generating sources for existing accounts without compromising on Profitability
- Completes social media marketing department operational requirements by scheduling and assigning employees and following up on work results

DIGITAL GLOBE SERVICES INC.

August 2014 – August 2017

Assistant Manager - Digital Marketing

- Successfully spearhead campaigns on social media platforms including Facebook and Instagram
- Manage social media planning for execution of marketing strategies and community management
- Managing agency account on Facebook from various industries including product and services marketing
- Making effective use of various Google Ads tool including Google Discovery, Display and Search network to make client's account grow further
- Evaluating customer data and insights to come up with creative ideas for Accounts
- Hands of experience of working on several Analysis tools including Google Analytic, Kenshoo, Microsoft Excel and Salesforce.com

Digital Clients

Client	Market	Industry	Ad Spend (Monthly)
Xfinity	USA	Telecom - B2C	\$300,000
Spectrum	USA	Telecom - B2C	\$75,000
AT&T	USA	Telecom - B2C	\$30,000
TeamViewer	EU	SaaS - B2B & B2C	\$25,000
Virgin Mobile	USA	Communication - B2C	\$600,000
ThreadBeast	USA	Subscription - B2C	\$400,000
ZenReach	USA	SaaS - B2B	\$200,000
Warranty People	UK	Warranty & Insurance - B2C	\$10,000
Khaadi	USA	eCommerce Clothing - B2C	\$15,000
AK Galleria	Pakistan	eCommerce Marketplace - B2C	\$40,000
Henna Guys	USA	Hair Dyes - B2C	\$20,000
Rizq Foundation - NGO	Pakistan	Donations	\$5,000
DaoPropTech	Pakistan	Real Estate - B2C	\$5,000
Vegamour	USA	eCommerce Cosmetics - B2C	\$10,000
Criquet Shirts	USA	eCommerce Clothing - B2C	\$10,000
Oladoc	Pakistan	Doctors Bookings - B2C	\$15,000
Service Market	UAE	Home Services - B2C	\$25,000
Pets Mania	Pakistan	eCommerce Pets Food - B2C	\$2,500
Maria B	Pakistan	eCommerce Luxury Clothing - B2C	\$10,000
Telvista	Pakistan	BPO Services - B2B	\$3,000
Souk Galleria	Pakistan	eCommerce Fragrance Store - B2C	\$2,500

Education LAHORE SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS – Lahore, PK

Jan 2015

MBA in Marketing - CGPA 3.63/4

LAHORE SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS – Lahore, PK

April 2013

BBA in Marketing - CGPA 3.55/4

Honors & Certifications

Meta Ads Media Planning Certification

Google Ads Search Certification

Google Ads Display Certification

Google Ads Digital Guru Expert 2021

Google Analytics Certification

Amazon Ads Certification

Microsoft Ads Accreditation

Microsoft Excel Training Workshop